Kheel, Theodore W. Legal Files 6021/004
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Theodore W. Kheel Legal Files
1956-1990
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Kheel, Theodore W.
6021/004
13.5 cubic feet
13.5 linear ft.
Papers.
5767567
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
MValadez, March 29, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 17, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Theodore Woodrow Kheel was said to be named for both Woodrow Wilson and his political rival Theodore Roosevelt, the result of a compromise between his politically differing parents. The settlement presaged a career in which Kheel would be tapped by mayors, governors, and presidents to settle disputes that were part of the nation's major political and social transitions from post-World War II to well into the 21st century.
Born in 1914 in Brooklyn, Ted Kheel attended public high school in the Bronx. He was awarded a Regents scholarship to Cornell University, where he attended an accelerated undergraduate law school program permitting him to earn a bachelor's and law degree in six years.
In private practice for a brief time after graduation from law school, Kheel soon was offered a position as a National Labor Relations Board attorney in Washington. Kheel's special talents as a mediator and his obvious political skills soon gave him the opportunity to move to a new war-time agency, where he was initially hired as principal mediation officer. By 1944, he had been appointed executive director of the National War Labor Board, with a staff of 2,500 who were hearing 150 disputes a week. Kheel's work at the WLB introduced him to the most important figures in the labor movement and key government officialscontacts he would use effectively in the future.
Following the end of World War II, Kheel returned to New York City and was drafted by Mayor O'Dywer to serve in the city's new Labor Relations Division, which Kheel came to head within a year. With the agreement of the mayor, Kheel was able to serve both in this position and maintain a separate, private law practice.
In 1949, Kheel was appointed to a part-time position as impartial chairman for an important segment of public transit in New York City, a position in which he would render 30,000 decisions through 1982. Also in 1949, Kheel became a partner in the New York law firm Battle, Fowler, Jaffin and Kheel. His skills in conflict resolution led an observer to remark that the firm's work began with a battle, ended by Kheel.
During his more than half a century of involvement in labor matters, Kheel was known above all else for his extraordinary ability to get feuding parties to make concessions to reach an agreement. In the important New York and national labor disputes which he would be called to mediate, Kheel's approach was to protect management rights and at the same time demand fairness to workers while also trying to protect the public interest in the issue.
Kheel's was frequently the voice of reason in settling a number of extremely difficult labor disputes of the 1960s and 1970s. Mayor Robert F. Wagner, Jr., turned to Kheel to help end the 114-day newspaper strike of 1962-63. Among his most infamous cases was the strike involving Mike Quill, head of the Transport Workers Union, who publically battled Mayor John V. Lindsay in 1965-66. Kheel's efforts also included helping coordinate bargainers and mediators during the 35-day New York City teachers' strike in 1968. President Lyndon B. Johnson summoned Kheel to Washington in 1964 to help mediate 10 days of feverish negotiations that prevented a nationwide rail walkout. Kheel would ultimately serve as a mediator and advisor for virtually every New York mayor from O'Dwyer to Beame, for the Kennedy-Johnson Administration, and other presidential administrations as well.
Kheel's interests in public issues were not limited to the labor sector. The policy disputes that came to his attention as a mediator and lawyer frequently cried out for larger solutions, and Kheel was not averse to using his considerable public presence and media contacts to seek redress, especially for what he viewed as past institutional injustices or misguided government actions. Although pressed to do so on a number of occasions, Kheel refused to run for elective office, preferring the role of a labor neutral and public advocate.
Kheel was also not averse to backing his powers of persuasion with legal action: a fierce advocate for public transit, he initiated a class action lawsuit over the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey's refusal to fund mass rail transit. His most sustained crusade for the public good related to his battle to limit commuter auto traffic and control highway building in New York City in favor of increased use of public transportation. Initially attacked by Port Authority officials and some city, state, and federal politicians of both parties, many of the solutions originally proposed by Kheel, including the concept of the subsidized fare, became public policy in later years.
An early supporter of the civil rights movement, Kheel and his wife Ann become involved with the New York Urban League in the 1950s. He served as its president in 1955 and as national president for four years. He worked with President Johnson on race issues and with Martin Luther King, Jr., in a libel suit against the New York Times. Kheel's mediation skills led to important strides in hiring African Americans in the airline industry. His reputation for sensitivity to minority issues resulted in his becoming involved in efforts to add civilians to the New York City Police Review Board in 1965. Kheel was also recruited as a peacemaker in the 1968 Ocean Hill-Brownsville Teachers dispute.
Even though Kheel handled disputes for transit workers, typesetters, and longshoremen, he reveled in the finer things in life, and dabbled as a restaurateur in fine food and was a patron of the fine arts.
He once owned a stake in Le Pavillon, a leading French restaurant in Manhattan, among others. He also represented numerous artists, including Robert Rauschenberg and Christo, and was the prime mover in the realization of the long-heralded Gates Project in Central Park in 2005.
He also made millions of dollars as an entrepreneur while facilitating sustainable economic and social change. He was the lead investor in the giant Punta Cana resort, transforming 30 miles of jungle in the Dominican Republic, and helped bring about the airport that opened that country to tourists and travelers.
Finding the solution to problems such as the impact of automation on the workplace, community disputes, and protecting a sustainable environment in which mankind will flourish, to name but a few, were the focus of Kheel's interest, enthusiasm, and financial support. He was the prime mover, bringing along like-minded citizens and specialists, in the creation of organizations to find solutions to the more intractable issues facing society. The Foundation on Employee Health, Medical Care and Welfare, the Foundation on Automation and Employment (and its British counterpart), Automation House, the Institute for Mediation and Conflict Resolution, and the Earth Pledge Foundation were among the most successful of such efforts. In the same vein, in collaboration with Price, Waterhouse in 1994, Kheel formed Prevention and Early Resolution of Conflicts, Inc. (PERC), now housed at Cornell ILR as Cornell/PERC Institute.
A prolific writer, Kheel is perhaps best known for his encyclopedic work on labor law. Throughout a career that was active almost until his death at age 96 in November 2010, he was able to balance, with amazing success, advocacy of the public good and the management of a successful law and mediation practice and other business and cultural interests.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5024: Theodore W. Kheel Arbitration Awards 5776 AV: Theodore W. Kheel Interviews and Programs 6017: Theodore W. Kheel Newspaper Clipping File 6021 AV: Theodore W. Kheel Audio-Visual Materials 6021 MB: Theodore W. Kheel Memorabilia 6021 P: Theodore W. Kheel Photographs 6021/001: Theodore W. Kheel Correspondence 6021/003: Theodore W. Kheel Arbitration files 6021/005: Theodore W. Kheel Speeches and Articles 6021/006: Theodore W. Kheel Non-Profit Organization Files 6021/007: Theodore W. Kheel Subject Files 6021/008: Theodore W. Kheel Books and Articles 6021/009: Theodore W. Kheel Newspaper Clipping File 6021/010: Theodore W. Kheel Additional Files 6021/011: Theodore W. Kheel Punta Cana Files 6021/012m: Invitation and Program for the Theodore W. Kheel Memorial Service 6059 OH: Thomas Shactman Interviews with Theodore W. Kheel 6194 OH: College of Labor and Employment Lawyers Interview with Theodore W. Kheel 6196 OH: New York City Central Labor Council Interview of Theodore W. Kheel for Central Archives 6207 OH: CLEL Video Oral History Project
Freeman, Jacob; Kheel, Theodore Woodrow; Lorant, Stefan; Children's Television Workshop; General Motors Corporation; National Broadcasting Company, inc.
5767567
- Drafts - CTW - 6677-2 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous - CTW - 6677-3 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- WGA Basic agreement - CTW - 6677-4 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Form of Writers Agreement - CTW - 6677-5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence and memos - CTW - 6677-1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Agreement - CTW-WGA - 6677-9, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- WGA Staff proposals - CTW - 6677-7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- CTW Counter-proposals - 6677-8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- CTW with AFRA - 6677-10 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- CTW with WGA - 6677-11 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Sesame Park - Children's Television Workshop - 6677-12 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- With DGA - Children's Television Workshop - 6677-13 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- With AFM - Children's Television Workshop - 6677-14 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- National student/parent mock election - Children's Television Workshop - 6677-15 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- NYC administration negotiations with city unions, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Lorant, Stefan (folder 1) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Lorant, Stefan (folder 2) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Lorant, Stefan (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Lorant, Stefan - 6064-002-1 - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1964-1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Correspondence - 6064-002-1 - Lorant, Stefan - Current, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Lorant, Stefan - 6064-002-1 - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Authors Edition Inc. - 6064-002-9 - Stefan Lorant (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Lorant, Stefan - Duplicates and drafts - 6064-002-2 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Lorant, Stefan - Agreements - 6064-002-3 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Lorant, Stefan - Miscellaneous - 6064-002-4 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Lorant, Stefan - Magnum Photos, Inc. and W. Eugene vs. Stefan Lorant - 6064-002-5 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Lorant, Stefan - Will - 6064-002-6 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Lorant, Stefan - Book "Labor in America" - 6064-002-7 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Lorant, Stefan - Material re. Lincoln book - 6064-002-8 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Book "Pittsburgh" - R.R. Donnelly and Sons Co. - 6064-002-10 - Stefan Lorant (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Dominican Republic book - 6064-002-11 - Stefan Lorant (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Sieg Heil - 6064-002-12 - Stefan Lorant (Box 2, Folder 17)
- "The Glorious Burden" - 6064-002-13 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Lorant, Stefan - Correspondence and memoranda - 6064-002-1, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Edward W. Dalheim et al. v. KDFW-TV (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Jacob Freeman v. National Broadcasting Co. - Exhibits A-D to Reply Affidavit (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Jacob Freeman v. National Broadcasting Co. - Volume II to affidavit of Jay E. Gerber (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Jacob Freeman v. National Broadcasting Co. - Deposition of plaintiff (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Jacob Freeman v. National Broadcasting Co. - Supplemental statement of material facts (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Jacob Freeman v. National Broadcasting Co. - Continued deposition of plaintiff (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Jacob Freeman v. National Broadcasting Co. - Affidavit of Jacob Freeman in opposition to defendant's summary judgment motion on behalf of all plaintiffs (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Jacob Freeman v. National Broadcasting Co. - Affidavit of Jacob Freeman in opposition to defendant's motion for summary judgment in his own case (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Wage and hour division article (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Jacob Freeman v. National Broadcasting Co. - Post-trial brief of plaintiffs Jacob Freeman, B.S. Brown, and Robert L. Garner (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Jacob Freeman v. NBC - NBC's reply memorandum (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Jacob Freeman v. NBC - Notice of appearance (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Jacob Freeman v. NBC - Statement of material facts (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Jacob Freeman v. NBC - Supplementary affidavit of Jacob Freeman (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Jacob Freeman v. NBC - Notice of cross motion for summary judgment in favor of Jacob Freeman, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Jacob Freeman v. NBC - Memorandum in support of NBC's motion for summary judgment (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Jacob Freeman v. NBC - Affidavit of Terry Baker in support of defendant's motion for summary judgment (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Jacob Freeman v. NBC - Affidavit of Jay Gerber (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Edward Dalheim v. KDFW-TV - Plaintiff's reply to defendant's post-trial brief (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Jacob Freeman v. NBC - Plaintiff Jacob A. Freeman's answers to defendant's first set of interrogatories, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Edward Dalheim v. KDFW-TV - Plaintiff's post-trial brief (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Edward Dalheim v. KDFW-TV - Defendant's reply to plaintiff's post-trial brief (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Deposition of Jacob Freeman - Initial conversation between attorneys, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Jacob Freeman v. NBC - Notice of motion, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Freeman v. NBC - NBC's memorandum re. Dalheim v. KDFW-TV, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Freeman v. NBC - Memorandum of law in opposition to defendant's summary judgment motion (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Freeman v. NBC - Index, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Supreme Court cases (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Dalheim v. KDFW-TV (Box 3, Folder 26)
- U.S. Court of Appeals - Thomas R. Sherwood v. The Washington Post, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Jacob Freeman v. NBC - Affidavit of Samuel M. Goodman, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Freeman v. NBC - Affidavit of Elizabeth McDermott, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Freeman v. NBC - Supplemental affidavit of William Wheatley, Jr., 1989 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Freeman v. NBC - Affidavit of William Baxter, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Freeman v. NBC - Plaintiff's exhibit 1 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Freeman v. NBC - Plaintiff's first request for admissions, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Freeman v. NBC - Original Complaint (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Freeman v. NBC - Individual answers to interrogatories (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Freeman v. NBC - Legal Research (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Freeman v. NBC - Drafts/notes (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Freeman v. NBC - NBC's post-trial brief, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Freeman v. NBC - NBC's answer, notices of deposition, defendant's request for production of documents, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Freeman v. NBC - Thomas L. Sherwood et al. v. The Washington Post (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Freeman v. NBC - Affidavit of Dan Grabel (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Freeman v. NBC - Protective order, stipulation and order, stipulation of fact (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Freeman v. NBC - Notice of motion for entry of motion and judgment (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Freeman v. NBC - Memorandum of law in support of motion for entry of order and judgment, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Freeman v. NBC - Notice of Hearing, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Freeman v. NBC - Transcript of Hearing, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Freeman v. NBC - Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Freeman v. NBC - Correspondence (folder 2) (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Jacob Freeman v. NBC - Orders (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Freeman v. NBC - Transcript of Hearing, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Freeman v. NBC - Report and recommendation, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Freeman v. NBC - Report and Recommendation, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Freeman v. NBC - Affidavit of Martin Ryan (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Freeman v. NBC - Defendant's interrogatories to certain plaintiffs (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Freeman v. NBC - Transcript of hearing, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Freeman v. NBC - Exhibits (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Freeman v. NBC - Affidavit of Lawrence S. Lapidus (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Freeman v. NBC - Memorandum in Support of Motion for Stay (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Freeman v. NBC - Memorandum endorsement, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Freeman v. NBC - Statement of disputed issues of fact (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Freeman v. NBC - Letters retaining TWK (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Christo - Re: 48 Howard St. (Freer Elevator Service Co.) (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Christo - Bibliography (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Christo - Re: Pont Neuf (Paris lawsuit) (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Christo - Re: 30 Downing St. (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Christo - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Christo - Legal Fees, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Meyer, Catalina K. (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Correspondence - 6695-1 - Marraccini, Francis and Nina and Conti Commodity Service Inc. (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Briefs - 6695-2 - Marraccini, Francis and Nina and Conti Commodity Service Inc. (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Drafts - 6695-3 - Marraccini, Francis and Nina and Conti Commodity Service Inc. (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Miscellaneous - 6695-4 - Marraccini, Francis and Nina and Conti Commodity Service Inc. (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Correspondence and Memos - 6678-1 - Karen Davis - Matter of Customs (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Notes and drafts - 6678-2 - Karen Davis - Matter of Customs (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Client's papers - 6678-3 - Karen Davis - Matter of Customs (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Miscellaneous - 6678-4 - Karen Davis - Matter of Customs (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Petition for relief - 6678-5 - Karen Davis - Matter of Customs (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Karen Davis - United States Court of International Trade Rules (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Correspondence and Memos - 6681-1 - Mascarotti (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Miscellaneous - 6681-2 - Mascarotti (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Correspondence and Memos - 6694-1 - Treesdale, Inc. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Corporate and minutes - 6694-2 - Treesdale, Inc. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous - 6694-3 - Treesdale, Inc. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Questionnaires - 6694-4 - Treesdale, Inc. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Financials - 6694-5 - Treesdale, Inc. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Correspondence - 6688-1 - Comstraw vs. UDC (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Court papers - 6688-2 - Comstraw vs. UDC (Box 5, Folder 7)
- General Motors Corp. - Re: Civil Action Suit, Better Ground Transportation (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Battery Park City (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Manhattan Landing Development Project (Box 6, Folder 3)
- OEG Legal Service Questionnaire (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Task Force on New York State Public Authorities (Box 6, Folder 5)
- State Charter Revision Commission (NYC) (Box 6, Folder 6)
- International Typographical Union (Box 6, Folder 7)
- New York City Convention Center (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Kheel vs. Murdoch et al. - 6692.A - Pleadings (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Kheel vs. Murdoch - 6692.A.1 - Correspondence file (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Kheel vs. Murdoch - 6692.A.2 - Litigation binder (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Kheel vs. Murdoch - 6692.A.2 - Litigation (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Kheel vs. Murdoch - Extra copies of correspondence (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Correspondence and memos - 6692.A.1 - Kheel vs. Murdoch, et al. (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Kheel vs. Murdoch - 6692 - Clippings (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Various extra copies - 6692 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Complaint-X-copies - 6692.A.2.1 - Kheel vs. Murdoch (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Miscellaneous - 6692-A.5 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Kheel vs. Murdoch - 6692-A.8 - Stirling Homex - Miscellaneous information (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Kheel vs. Murdoch - 6692-A.9 - ABT-GRAIVER - Miscellaneous information (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Copies - 6692-A.3 - Kheel vs. Murdoch, et al (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Drafts - 6692-A.3 - Kheel vs. Murdoch, et al. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Kheel vs. Murdoch - 6692-A.10 - AP Clips (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Newspaper clippings - 6692-A.6 - Kheel vs. Murdoch, et al. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Kheel vs. Murdoch - 6692-A.7 - Research (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Kheel vs. Murdoch - "Why New York Magazine Refused to Accept My Ad", 1979 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Kheel v. NYC Port Authority (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Port Authority press releases by other people (Box 7, Folder 11)
- United States Trust Co. of NY v. the state of New Jersey et al. - Docket No. L-26861-73 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Theodore W. Kheel, G. Oliver Koppell, et al. v. the Port of the New York Authority - 71Civ.956 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Port Authority Court Papers (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Gaby v. Port Authority of New York and New Jersey - L-26462-71 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Kheel on behalf of himself and all other citizens v. Port of NY Authority Index No. 00996/73 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Kheel et al. v. Port of New York Authority - No. 72-323 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Kheel, Koppell, et al. v. Port of New York Authority - Docket No. 71-1917 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Port of New York Authority - Official statement - Consol. Bonds. (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Port Authority legislation - Encl. Copies of bills to Senate, reports, laws (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Port Authority correspondence by Kheel, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Port Authority news clips (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Transcript of record in the Omar Inc. and Bakery Sales Drivers Local Union 244 (folder 1) (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Transcript of record in the Omar Inc. and Bakery Sales Drivers Local - Union 244 (folder 2) (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Transcript of record in the Omar Inc. and Bakery Sales Drivers Local Union 244 (folder 3) (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Maison Jomere Ltd. (Box 8, Folder 4)
- 91. Miscellaneous (3 of 7 Sp) - National Conference of Christians and Jews - Misc. corresp. - 99290.900 - Kheel, Theodore W. - Re: personal (Box 8, Folder 5)
- 91. Misc. (3 of 7 Sp) - National Conference of Christians and Jews - Grievance procedure corr. - 99290.900 - Kheel, Theodore W. - Re: personal (Box 8, Folder 6)
- 91. Misc. (3 of 7 Sp) - National Conference of Christians and Jews - Bylaws - 99290.900 - Kheel, Theodore W. - Re: personal (Box 8, Folder 7)
- 91. Misc. (3 of 7 Sp) - National Conference of Christians and Jews - Personnel manual - 99290.900 - Kheel, Theodore W. - Re: personal (Box 8, Folder 8)
- 91. Misc. (3 of 7 Sp) - National Conference of Christians and Jews - Financial stats - 99290.900 - Kheel, Theodore W. - Re: personal (Box 8, Folder 9)
- 91. Misc. (3 of 7 Sp) - National Conference of Christians and Jews - Board of Trustees - 99290.900 - Kheel, Theodore W. - Re: personal (Box 8, Folder 10)
- McGraw-Hill, Inc. - Re: Inter-Maritime Forwarding Co. (Box 8, Folder 11)
- King Arthur Productions Inc. - Arthur Barren - Re: Proposed documentary film "The Contract" (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Billy Kluver - Loan agreement with Numeroff and Kluver (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Kluver, Billy (Box 8, Folder 14)
- IFFA Re: TWA petition before the Department of Transportation (folder 1) (Box 8, Folder 15)
- IFFA Re: TWA petition before the Department of Transportation (folder 2) (Box 8, Folder 16)
- IFFA v. TWA (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Correspondence and memoranda - 6617-1 - Economic Stabilization Program (Box 8, Folder 18)
- NYS Board of Elections - Guide to Requirements of NYS Election Law Related to Campaign Spending (Box 8, Folder 19)
- News releases - 6007-15 - Theodore W. Kheel et al. v. Edward I. Koch et al. (Box 8, Folder 20)
- District Attorney correspondence - 6007-21 - Kheel v. Koch (Box 8, Folder 21)
- New York Supreme Court - Gilbert Dilucia v. Lawrence A. Mandelker (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Reply affidavit - 6007-13 - Kheel v. Koch (Box 8, Folder 23)